In this video, I'm going to talk about the reason why we want to combine many models
在这个视频中 我将探讨为什么我们想要使用多个模型的结合
when we're making predictions. If we have a single model, we have to
进行预测 如果我有一个模型 我必须
choose some capacity for it. If we choose too little capacity, it would
选择模型的容量 如果模型的容量太小 该模型
be able to fit the regularities in the training data.
将不能适应训练数据的一致性
And if we choose too much capacity, it won't be able to fit the sampling error in
如果模型的容量过大 该模型将不能适应训练数据的样本错误
the particular training set we have. By using many models, we can actually get
通过结合多个模型 我们可以
a better tradeoff between fitting the true regularities, and overfitting the sampling
在拟合数据的一致性和过度拟合样本的误差之间
error in the data. At the start of the video,
取得一个更好的权衡 在这一讲的视频的开头
I'll show you that when you average models together, you can expect to do better than
我将证明当你一起使用各个模型 你可以期待这些模型
any single model. This effect is largest when the models
将会比任何单一模型有更好性能 当这些模型
make very different predictions from each other.
每个模型都做出了非常不同的预测
And at the end of this video, I'll discuss various ways in which we can encourage the
在这一讲视频的结束 我将会讨论
different models to make very different predictions.
可以鼓励不同模型 做出非常不同的预测的多个方法
As we've seen before, when we have a limited amount of training data, we tend
正如我们之前所见 当我们的训练数据有限 我们容易
to get overfitting. If we average the predictions of many
过度拟合这些数据 如果我们平均各个模型的
different models we can typically reduce that overfitting.
不同预测 我们通常可以减少过度拟合
This helps most when the models make very different predictions from one another.
这非常有用 特别是当各个模型都做出了非常不同的预测
For regression, the squared arrow can be decomposed into a bias term and a variance
对于回归分析 squared arrow可以被分解为一个偏差项和
term. And that allows us to analyze what's going
一个方差项 这可以帮助我们分析正在发生什么
on. The bias term is big if the model has too
如果模型只有很小的容量去适应数据
little capacity to fit the data. It measures how poorly the model
偏差项会比较大 它能测量这个模型
approximates the true function. The variance term is big if the model has
与真正的函数有多么不同 如果模型
so much capacity that it's good at modeling the sampling error in our
的容量很大 在我们特定的训练集里 可以很好地处理样本误差
particular training set. So, it's called variance, because if we go
方差项会比较大 所以称之为方差
and get another training set of the same size from the same distribution, our model
因为如果我们有另外一个训练集 有着相同的大小和分布 我们的模型
will fit differently to that training set, because it has different sampling error.
将会对这个训练集有非常不同的拟合 因为它有不同的样本误差
And so we'll get variance in the way the models fit to different training sets.
因此当用模型拟合不同的训练集时 我们将会得到方差
If we average models together, what we're doing is we're averaging away the
如果我们将多个模型放到一起平均 我们正在做的是平均掉方差
variance, And that allows us to use individual
这将允许我们使用单独的
models that have high capacity and therefore high variance.
有着大容量 以及高方差的模型
These high capacity model typically have low bias.
这些大容量模型通常有较低的偏差
So we can get the low bias without incurring the high variance by using
所以当我们有了更低的偏差 并且可以使用平均减少方差
averaging to get rid of the variance. So now let's try and analyze how an
避免出现高方差 现在我们尝试一下并分析
individual model compares with an average of models.
比较独立的模型和多个模型的平均吧
On any one test case some individual predictors may be better than the combined
在任何测试下 一些独立模型可能会比
predictor. The different individual predictors will
混合模型有更好的预测结果 不同的独立模型会
be better on different cases. And if the individual predictors disagree
在不同的情况下有更好的结果 如果这些独立模型的结果非常不同
a lot, the combined predictor is typically better than all of the individual
当我们平均所有测试例
predictors when we average over test cases.
混合模型通常会有更好的预测结果
So we should aim to make the individual predictors disagree, without making them
所以我们要使独立模型有不同的结果 并且不会使他们
be poor predictors. The art is to have individual predictors
性能下降 方法是使每个独立模型
that make very different errors from one another, but are each fairly accurate.
之间都有非常不同的误差 但是它们每个都是相当准确的
So, now let's look at the math and what happens when we combine networks.
现在我们来看看数学 已经当我们组合网络时会发生什么
We're going to compare two expected squared errors.
我们将会比较两种期望平方误差
The first expected squared error is the one we get if we pick one of the
第一个期望平方误差是 如果我们随机选择一个模型
predictors at random and use that for making our predictions.
用它做出预测
And then what we do is we average overall predictors, the error we'd expect to get
然后我们平均所有的模型 如果我们按照这个方式
if we followed that policy. So Y bar is the average of what all the
得到的误差就是第一个期望平方误差 所以Y平均是
predictors say, and YI is what an individual predictor says.
所有模型预测结果的平均 Yi是其中一个模型的结果
So Y bar is just the expectation over all the individual predictors I of YI and I'm
所以Y平均只是对Yi中所有独立模型i的总体期望
using those angle brackets to represent an expectation, where the thing that comes
我将会用这些尖括号表示期望
after the angle bracket tells you what it's an expectation over.
所以尖括号就是表示 它是一个总期望
We can write the same thing as one over n times the sum overall of the n of the yi.
我们可以将它写成 N分之1乘上所有N个模型的和
Now, if we look at the expected squared error we'd get if we chose a predictor at
现在如果我们观察期望平方误差 将会知道我们是否随机选择了
random, What we'd have to do is compare that
模型 我们需要做的是比较
predictor with the target, take the squared difference.
模型和目标的 并对差进行平方
And then average that over all predictors. That's also on the left hand side there.
再对所有模型平均 它也在左手边
If I simply add a Y bar and subtract a Y bar, I don't change the value.
如果我简单得加上一个Y平均再减去一个Y平均 我不会改变它的值
And now it's going to be easier to do some manipulations.
现在我们可以更容易地 对式子做一些整理
I can now multiply it that squared and inside this expectation bracket I have t
我现在可以展开平方式 在期望括号里有t
minus y bar squared, y I minus y bar square, and t minus y bar into y I minus y
减去y平均并平方 yi减去y平均 t减去y平均 乘上yi减去y平均
bar, which has the c will disappear. So the first term, T minus Y bar squared,
这样c会消失 所以第一项 T减去Y平均的差的平方
doesn't have an I in it anymore, and so we can forget about the expectation brackets
不再有i 所以我们可以将这一项从期望括号里面提出来
for that. That really is T minus Y bar squared.
然后得到单独的T减去Y平均的差的平方
And that's the squared arrow you'd get if you compared the average of the models
如果你比较模型的平均和目标 这就是平方误差
with the target. And our aim is to show the thing on the
我们的目标是
left hand side is bigger than that, i.e., by using that average, we've reduced the
证明左边部分更大 就是通过使用平均 我们可以减少
expected squared error. So the extra term we have on the right
期望平方误差 所以右边的多余的项
hand side, is the expectation of y i minus y bar squared.
是y i 减去y平均的差的平方的期望
And that's just the variance of the y i. It's the expected squared difference
也就是yi的平方差 它是yi和y平均之间的
between y I and y bar. And then the last tone disappears, it
期望平方差 然后消掉最后一项
disappears because the difference of Y I from Y bar we expect to be uncorrelated
我们可以消掉它是因为 我们期望的Y到Yi的差是与
with the difference between the arrow that the average of the networks makes on the
网络的平均产生的误差和目标之间的差 是无关的
target. And so we're multiplying together two
所以我们乘上两个部分的
things that are zero mean and uncorrelated and we expect to get zero on average.
平均是0 且无关的 我们期望平均是0
So the result is that the expected squared error we get by picking a model at random
所以结果我们通过随机选择模型 得到的期望平方误差
is greater than the squared error we get by averaging the models by the variance of
它比我们通过平均模型的输出方差 得到期望平方误差大
the outputs of the models. That's how much we win by when we take an
这是我们通过一个平均提高的量
average. So, I want to show you that in a picture.
现在来看看这个图示
So, along the horizontal line, we have the possible values of the output, and in this
沿着平行的线 我们有输出的可能值
case, all of the different models predict a value that is too high.
在这种情况下 所有不同的模型预测的值都太高
The predictors that are further than average from T make bigger than average
这些离平均t很远的预测 会产生更大的平均方差
squared errors, like that bad guy in red, and the predictors that are less than the
就像那个红色的bad guy 那些比平均值离t更近的模型
average distance from T make smaller than average squared arrows.
会产生更小的平方差
And the first effect dominates, because we're using squared error.
第一种影响占主要位置 因为我们将会用方差
So if you look at the math, let's suppose that the good guy and the bad guy were
所以从数学角度来说 让我们假设good guy和bad guy
equally far from the mean. So the average squared error they make is
距离平均同样远 所以他们产生的平均方差
Y bar minus epsilon squared plus Y bar plus epsilon squared.
是Y平均减去epsilon的平方加上 Y的平均加上epsilon的平方
And when we work that out, we get the squared error that the mean of the
当我们算出这个式子 我们就得到的方差就是
predictors makes, plus an epsilon squared. So we win by averaging predictors before
模型预测结果平均的平方加上epsilon的平方 所以我们通过平均预测结果
we compare them with the target. That's not always true.
在将他们与目标比较前得到我们想要的 这并不总是对的
It depends very much on using a squared error.
这非常依赖于使用平方差
If, for example, you have a whole bunch of clocks.
举例来说 如果你有很多钟表
And you try and make them more accurate by averaging them all,
你想通过平均它们显示时间的方式 将它们调得更精确
That'll be a disaster. And it'll be a disaster because the noise
这无疑是一场灾难 因为你所期待的这些钟表的误差
you expect in clocks isn't Gaussian noise. What you expect is that, many of them will
并不是高斯分布 你期待的是 很多表只有很小的误差
be very slightly wrong and a few of them will have stopped or will be wildly wrong.
其中很少一部分不走 或者有很大误差
And if you average, you make sure they are all significantly wrong, which is not what
如果你平均的话 你只会让他们的误差更加错得离谱
you want. The same thing applies to the discrete
这同样可以应用到离散分布
distribution as we have our class labeled probabilities.
因为我们有标记分级的概率
So suppose that we have two models, and one gives the correct label of probability
所以假设我们有两个模型 其中一个给了Pi概率一个正确的标签
of Pi, and the other gives the correct label of probability of Pj.
另外一个给了Pj概率一个正确的标签
Is it better to pick one model at random, or it is it better to average those two
这时候最好随机选择 还是最好将两者的概率平均
probabilities, and predict the average of Pi and Pj.
并预测Pi和Pj的平均
What if I had a measure is the log probability of getting the right answer?
如果我有一个log概率的可能性得到正确的结果 会怎么样?
Then, the log of the average of Pi and Pj is going to be a better bet than the log
那么Pi和Pj的平均的log 将会好过Pi的log加上Pj的log然后再平均
of Pi plus the log of Pj averaged. That's most easily seen in a diagram
使用图像的话更好理解
because of the shape of the log function. So that black curve is the log.
因为它是一个log函数的形状 所以黑色的线是log函数
On the horizontal access I've drawn Pi and Pj,
在水平轴上 我画了Pi和Pj
And the gold colored line, joins log Pi to log Pj.
那条黄色线 连接log Pi到log Pj
You can see that if we first start with Pi and Pj together, to get that average value
你可以看到如果你首先从Pi和Pj一起开始
at the blue arrow is, and then we compute the log, we get that blue dot.
在蓝色箭头上得到的平均 然后我们计算log 得到蓝色点
Whereas if we first take the log of pi, and separately take the log of pj, and
虽然如果你首先计算Pi的log 并分开计算Pj的log
then we average those two logs, we get the mid-point of that gold line,
然后我们平均两个log 得到黄色线的中点
Which is below the blue dot. So to make this averaging be a big win, we
这个点比蓝色点低 所以我们那样做非常有优势
want our predictors to differ by a lot. And there's many different ways to make
我们希望我们的模型非常不同 要达到这个目的有很多种方式
them differ. You could just rely on a learning
你可以直接依赖学习算法
algorithm that doesn't work too well, and get stuck in different local optima each
但效果并不好 每次都会卡在不同的局部优化
time. It's not a very intelligent thing to do,
所以说这样方式很不明智
but it's worth a try. You could use lots of different kinds of
但是它依然值得去尝试 你可以尝试很多不同类型的模型
models, including ones that are not neural networks.
包括不是神经网络的那些
So, it makes sense to try decision trees, Gaussian process models, support vector
这使得尝试决策树变得很有意义 高斯处理模型 支持向量机
machines. I'm not explaining any of those in this
我不会在这个课程中介绍它们
course. In Andrew Ng's machine on Coursera, you
在Coursera上Andrew Ng的机器学习课程中
can learn about all those things. Well you could try many other different
你可以学到那些知识 虽然你可以尝试很多不同的模型
kinds of model. If you really want to use a bunch of
如果你真的想用一堆不同的神经网络模型
different neural-network models, you can make them different by using a different
你可以把它们变得不同 通过使用不同数量的
number of hidden layers or a different number of units per layer or different
隐藏层 或在每个层使用不同数量的单元
types of unit. Like in some nets you could use
或者不同类型的单元 类似于你在一些网络中可以使用
rectified-linear units, And in other nets you could use logistic
修正线性单元 在另外一些网络你使用逻辑单元
units. You could use different types or strengths
可以使用不同类型或强度的权重衰减
of weight penalty. So you might use early stopping for some
所以你可能对一些网络使用提前停止策略
nets, and an L2 weight penalty for others, and an L1 weight penalty for others.
以及对一些的一个L2权重惩罚 对另外一些的一个L1权重惩罚
You could use different learning algorithms.
你可以使用不同的学习算法
So for example you could use full batch for some, and mini batch for others, if
所以如果你的数据集足够小 对于一些例子来说你可以使用全批量full batch
your data set is small enough to allow that.
对另外一些实用迷你全量
You can also make the models differ by training the models on different training
你也可以通过使用不同训练数据训练模型的方式 得到不同的模型
data. So, there's a method introduced by Leo
有一种方式最初由Leo Breiman介绍
Breiman called bagging, where you train different models on different subsets of
称为套袋 你可以使用不同的数据子集得到不同的模型
the data. And you get these subsets by sampling the
并且你能通过对训练集取样替换 得到子集
training set with replacement. So we sampled a training set that had
所以我们对一个有样本A B C D的训练集取样
examples A, B, C, D, and E. And we got five examples, but we'll have
得到五个样本
some missing and some duplicated. And we train one of our models on that
但是我们会漏掉一些或者重复一些 我们训练一个模型在这个特定的训练集上
particular training set. This is done in a method called random
这些会在一个称为随机森林的方法下完成
forest that uses bagging with decision trees, which Leo Breiman was also involved
它使用bagging结合了决策树 这也是由Leo Breiman参与发明的
in inventing. When you train decision trees with bagging
当你使用bagging训练决策树
and then average them together, they work much better than single decision tree bys
然后将它们平均 会好过任何单个决策树的
themselves. In fact, the connect box uses random
事实上 连接箱子使用了随机森林
forests to convert information about depth into information about where your body
来将关于深度的信息转换成 关于你的主体部分在哪的信息
parts are. We could use bagging with neural nets, but
我们可以使用bagging结合神经网络
it's very expensive. If you wanted to train say, twenty
但是这样代价很大 如果你想使用这种方式训练 比如说20个
different neural nets this way, you'd have to get your twenty different training
不同的神经网络 你需要有20个不同的训练集
sets. And then it would take twenty times as
与训练单个网络相比 这将花费20倍的时间
long as training one net. That doesn't matter with decision tress
这对于决策树是没有关系的
cuz they're so fast to train. Also, at test time, you'd have to run
因为它们训练速度很快 并且在测试时 你需要运行
these twenty different nets. Again, with decision trees, that doesn't
20个不同的网络 对于决策树来说 这依然不是问题
matter, cuz they're so fast to use at test time.
因为他们在测试时运行非常快
Another method for making the training data different is to train each model on
另外一个制作不同训练数据的方法是 使用整个数据集训练每个模型
the whole training set, But to weight the cases differently So, in
但是给不同列子不同的权重
boosting, we typically we use a sequence of fairly low capacity models.
所以在boosting 我们通常使用一系列 更小容量的模型
And we weight the training cases for each model differently.
然后我们给每个模型的训练例不同的权重
What we do is we up weight the cases the previous model got wrong and we down
我们将要做的事就是在前一个模型出错的时候 提高权重
weight the case of previous model got right.
在前一个模型正确的时候 降低权重
So the next model in the sequence doesn't waste its time trying to model cases that
所以序列中的下一个模型 不会浪费它自己的时间去尝试对
are already correct. It uses its resources to try to deal with
已经正确的情况做匹配 它使用它的资源去处理那些其他模型出错的例子
cases the other models are getting wrong. An early use of boosting, was with neural
boosting的一个早期使用目的是结合神经网络 处理MNIST
nets for MNIST, And there when computer's are actually
在电脑非常慢的时候
slower. One of the big advantage is was that it
其中一个大优势就是它
focused to competitional resources on modelling the tricky cases,
集中使用它的资源处理那些需要处理的例
And didn't waste a lot of time, going over easy cases again and again.
这样不会浪费很多时间 一次又一次得处理简单的例子